[Music]
IL Cafe we have you
covered hello and welcome everybody to
Il Cafe digital business your goto
podcast for insights on the evolving
landscape of digital transformation in
the insurance industry I'm aalia keeping
you company today hopping on the the
series luckily and very very glad to be
here now today we have a very special
guest from ICI Lombard joining us uh you
please introduce yourself for our
audience
ma'am hi aelia it's a pleasure to be on
this podcast today and I'm zenat mongal
from IC Lombard it's been eight years in
this organization and I can't believe it
myself the time has just flown by and
just to give you a little bit more on
myself so I have over about two decades
of experience in in light uh in
delighting customers helping empowering
them with innovative solutions working
on customer process Etc so that's about
my experience my insurance this is my
first tint with ICA Lombard but it's
been some Journey I tell you full of
learning uh roll it is a it has been a
roller coaster Journey but a good one
not a bad one so I'm enjoying the ride
thoroughly and uh I'll take you through
some experiences and hope you enjoy the
journey of IA Lombard which I'm going to
share on this podcast today absolutely
I'm sure that we will and you know as
someone who hasn't even been on a roller
coaster I'm just going to take your word
for it
okay and ailia just to also tell you at
icsl of my current role is I'm taking
care of the customer experience and this
team is almost about three years old and
uh has been uh we've been working on
digital Transformations for the cust for
enhancing customer experiences and
empowering customers okay fantastic good
to know Zena and you know that's very
useful I think you're the perfect person
for to be talking to on today's podcast
because we're going to be covering a
range of those topics that you just
mentioned and you know what it also
feels like this is your passion really
uh so that's going to shine through as
well so you know to start us off Zena
why don't we uh take a look at how
consumer Behavior really is changing you
know with Indian consumers becoming a
lot more digital forward uh how is this
going to impact the insurance sector and
how does the insurance sector sort of
come into play
here see if you look at today's consumer
today's consumer is ordering grocery on
apps like Amazon blinket big basket so
even for very very um uh basic things
there is digital technology and the
ecommer of the world like the Amazon of
the world have ensured that they've
taught the customer how to use apps
understand what are nuanes of UI and
thanks to the Googles of the world they
have told they have educated the
customer with artificial intelligence
concepts of machine learning Etc so in a
nutshell today's customer is very very
digital Savvy and if you have to put it
in the insurance Nuance at the time of
purchase we have the maximum involvement
of the customer because this product the
motor product if you talk about it is a
compulsory product through compliance
and Regulatory but when it comes to a
health product customer is extremely
careful wants to know everything in
advance and in detail so he would like
to he or she would like to check online
as well as coordinate very closely with
the salesperson to understand and to
understand every Nuance of the health
product and therefore we have to be out
there with our digital Solutions because
after purchase he wants to be left alone
whether it is a claim whether it is any
service related uh aspect that he wants
so we thought that uh not we thought it
was imperative for us to be out there
with the concept of concepts of machine
learning applying artificial
intelligence we needed to have the um uh
artificial intelligence enabled Bots Etc
and that's what it is that's really
interesting you know zenat also goes to
show that in today's market right no
matter what the sector is we're also in
some sense keeping up with the
consumer's expectations as it should be
um now to take from your point of AI and
ml's involvement in you know developing
these new age digital solutions for our
consumers could you maybe talk about
some tangible examples of AIML
involvement in these developments uh at
ICI Lombard that have actually been used
to enhance customer
experience sure so I'll go back I'll
take you back down the memory lane when
Co struck India so to be with the
customer virtually we had to
have Technologies we had to use the
Technologies of artificial intelligence
and machine learning and therefore we
introduce Ria and we didn't want to lose
the human connect now let me introduce
you to Ria Ria is a responsive
intelligent assistant she is our human
uh ofar the first U industry first human
ofar customer communication mascot she
is our face for the customer so she's
available on conversation AI as well as
on voice AI so let me help you
understand conversational Ai and voice
AI conversational AI is nothing but the
chat platforms so chat platforms most
popularly use is WhatsApp and our
website also we have R working as a chat
bot voice AI on our toll-free number 1
80026 which is our tollfree number so
Ria introduces or opens the call Welcome
to IC Lombard how can I help you today
so she has she's our voice bot as well
she speaks in two languages English and
Hindi she is NLP enabled she's able to
understand the natural language
processing part of it and she also is
there on a new technology called the
visual Assist ivr Technology this
technology we have leveraged for use
cases where we need data entry for
customer so if there is a claim
intimation if there is a policy
endorsement or a policy modification
that needs to be done where we need
customer to key in some information we
using the visual Assist ivr
Technology okay you know what that's
really fascinating um if I may just ask
a spontaneous question about Ria why was
that name
picked so Ria's name was picked by our
current MD and CEO Mr sanjie mantri we
were contemplating a lot of names when
we were when Ria was born so Ria became
three Ria just turned three on the 8th
of March her birthday is on
International women's day and we wanted
to capture the essence of Ria being uh
responsive so that's um responsive is
she is very responsive to whatever you
ask her intelligent she is because she
uses artificial intelligence at the back
end and yes she's your virtual assistant
so Ria is a responsive intelligent
assistant and that's
why fantastic and a happy belated
birthday to R um but to talk about yeah
to talk about the special girl a little
bit more can we also dive into some you
know specific examples of where Ria's
capabilities have actually made a
significant impact on you know our
customer engagement has that seen a
sufficient
increase increase my God she is a brat I
tell you the way she's grown over the
last three years so when we introduced
Ria she was introduced to handle motor
claim intimation okay and now motor
claim intimation when we started our
journey she was doing only about 500 600
motor claim interations at the uh on R
were managed by briia today she's doing
about
20,000 wow claim intimations without any
human intervention so what does that
mean for the customer m in the event of
an unfortunate accident when the
customer calls at any time 24 by7 V is
able to take the claim intimation on the
go and uh this is about 90% of the claim
inations that we receive at the call
center so only the balance 10% are done
humanly rest 90% is what Ria is managing
for motor claim
intimations wow fantastic Journey yeah
no if only we sort of progressed at that
rate right with every birthday yes and
every birthday now she's doing about if
I have to give you some monthly numbers
on WhatsApp alone she's doing about more
more than
170,000 transactions in a month that's
WhatsApp alone and these include policy
downloads claim intimations providing
claim status informing or not informing
sharing the policy coverage and benefits
with the customer helping customers link
their mobile numbers find out branches
branch locations find out hospital
locations everything is done
by fantastic very clear to see that you
know these kind of technological
advancements being adopted at ICI
Lombard are helping us you know uh
remain uh a game changer right in in the
market and in the sector really
commendable stuff there um you know
another aspect Zena if we were to bring
into this conversation now is the aspect
of cost-saving and operational
efficiency right that's a big um sort of
sell or value ad that AI technology and
digital first sort of adaptation brings
into the big picture so can you talk
talk to us a little bit about how ICI
Lombard has leveraged technological
innovations um and automation to really
achieve cost saving within the
organization so uh it's a great question
and without these results just
leveraging technology and enhancing
customer experience really does not make
uh much sense so to uh give you a sneak
peak into the cost savings when we
started our digital transformation
Journey we were doing about
250,000 contacts at call center so
contacts is transactions at the call
center which is our customer
relationship team and as we speak today
we're doing about
500,000 service transactions so our
service transactions have doubled with a
43% reduced manpow so instead of adding
manpower to handle 500,000 transactions
we reduced 43% of our head count at our
call center and we double the
transactions so that's the kind of
savings that we're talking about over
the period of last three years that's
really an amazing achievement uh Zena
thank you so much for bringing that to
the four on today's podcast um and
that's the kind of stuff you know we
always say we got to see it to believe
it right well numbers don't really lie
and that's proof enough that we're on
the right track um very very eye opening
now we've reached the end of today's
podcast quite swiftly I might add Zena
but as we wrap up could you maybe share
your vision for the future of customer
experience within ICI Lombard as you
mentioned in the beginning of the
podcast it is something you're quite
passionate
about oh yes so gen aai is the new um
term have you heard about it AIA yes
generative AI I have yeah so that's the
Talk of the Town and we are on it and
very lately in last month I think March
end we introduced gen AI to simplify the
policy for the customer so with Gen AI
customer can know his policy coverage
and benefits in a simplified term and
currently it's under beta but yes we are
out there with Gen we have many other
use cases coming using the power of
generative AI That's on the cards
immediately then we are also looking at
uh the 3D avar of Ria today she's in 2D
3D avar is soon to come and uh she'll be
all out there in the 3D this the other
is we looking at now we looked at
service transactions now we'll move to
some sales transactions digitizing the
sales transactions we look at how can we
renew policies without human human
intervention so we do have one such use
case which we are uh doing on WhatsApp
which is the motor renewal so two
wheeler and four-wheeler renewals we
have explored and we have experimented
with WhatsApp and many more to come on
the sales side of it so service
transactions mostly uh there will be
other use cases of course coming in in
the service transactions but now our key
focus is on uh promoting the unassisted
sales Journeys starting with
renewals okay fantastic well it seems
like we're on a very exciting path it's
not just you know an important and
valuable one but also exciting for
everyone involved uh and Ria's
involvement as well uh thank you so very
much Zena for you know not only your
insights today but also your passion and
true love for customer experience enhan
M here at IC lombar I think we can all
take a little bit of that spirit and
move in the right direction thanks so
much for joining us on this edition of I
Cafe thank you aelia before you just
wind up I um I kind of wanted to also
share that uh there are many first
industry first initiative amongst all
that we told you so the motor claim
inations we were the first one using
visual assist ivr uh for giving motor
claim inations on the digital platform
similarly I told you the human of bought
was first of its kind and um yeah these
are mostly industry first initiatives
before I thought before I go I should
share with my audience that these were
pineur by lomard yeah fantastic I mean
it might not be the best but you know
kind keep the best for the last awesome
absolutely thanks so much Zena for your
time and for being with us on I Cafe
today everyone stay tuned we'll keep
bringing you more stories uh you know of
our digital transformation Journey here
at ICI Lombard but in the meantime stay
safe and stay happy pleasure to be
pleasure the pleasure is all mine thank
you for having me here have a great day
and a weekend everyone stay safe thank
you so much